FELIX TSOWA

FRONT-END ENGINEER



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm a passionate and astute Front-End Engineer with 4+ years of experience. I take interest in using my skill to develop creative, interactive and responsive UI on product for companies. I valued fast learning and growing work environment. I'm an expertise in developing user-friendly applications while following the latest design and development trends.

TOOLS

HTML, CSS, BOOTSTRAP, TAILWIND, CSS-IN-JS, SCSS, LESS, JAVASCRIPT, TYPESCRIPT, REACT JS, NEXT JS, VITE, GATSBY JS, SVELTE, REACT NATIVE, VUE JS, NODE JS, MONGODB, EXPRESS JS, REDUX, MOBX, RECOIL, REACT-QUERY, GIT, GITHUB, JEST, REACT-TESTING-LIBRARY, REST API, FORMIK, YUP, DOCKER, GRAPHQL, APOLLO, FIGMA, SWIPER JS, SOLID JS, ADOBE PHOTOSHOP, WEBSOCKET, JIRA, BOOSTRAP, ANT DESIGN, MATERIAL UI, FRAMER-MOTION.

CONTACT

+234 9032328670

https://github.com/felixNT0

NO 10, FHA, Abuja.

https://portfolio-seven-sigma-53.vercel.app/

EDUCATION

Federal University of Technology, Minna. Bachelor of Statistic

SKILLS

- · Critical Thinking and brainstorming.
- High level problem solving.
- Excellent communication and collaboration.

HOBBIE

- Learning new things.
- · Reading.
- Playing Musical Instruments.
- · Gaming.
- Playing Football.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer

March 2022 - Present

- Experienced with developing reusable react component.
- Collaborated with the product design team for UI design implementation using Figma.
- Experienced with unit test and integration test.
- Contributed to code reviewing on GitHub.
- Experienced working in Agile development environment, using JIRA.
- Experienced working in Remote environment and using collaborative tools like Slack and Google workspace

Web and Mobile Developer

Feb 2020 - July 2021

InvestYield (https://www.investyield.ng)

InvestYield-App (https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.investyield)

- Identify problem uncovered by testing on customer feedback and correct problems or refer problems to appropriate personnel for correction.
- Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature in developments.
- Worked closely with the ceo and clients in converting there ideas into real applications.

Front-End Developer

Califonia USA, Sept 2021 - March 2022

Paperdaz (https://www.paperdaz.com)

- With a team of developers we build web applications for clients.
- Extensive usage of REACT packages like react-redux and react-query.
- Worked closely with the ceo and clients in converting there ideas into real applications.
- Wrote unit tests in Jest to ensure code was tested and 100% bug free.